When David talked about how much data qualifies as big data,
David 在解释大数据的概念时
he went through an example of how we can potentially
他提出了一种做法或者思路
analyse big file by dividing it into smaller pieces,
我们可以将大的数据分解成小份
sending the chunks to our colleagues,
把一份份数据发给我们的同事
running the processing in parallel,
进行并行计算
and then collecting the results.
然后搜集结果
The spherical resembles the MapReduce logic quite closely.
这个逻辑和 MapReduce 的逻辑很相似
All those pride provides higher level abstractions and in-memory computation,
尽管这个是高级别的抽象化且是内存计算
it's useful to know a bit more about the idea that inspired it.
所以多了解一下其想法的来源是有用的
Let's use MapReduce on a four node cluster to calculate
让我们在带 4 个节点的集群上使用MapReduce 来计算
how many times each song was played in the last year in our music streaming service.
去年我们平台每首歌被播放的次数
Since our company has grown quite larget,
因为我们公司现在已经很大了
the log data containing all these events is
存储事件的日志数据有好几百G
hundreds of gigs and cannot be processed on a single machine.
所以没法在一台机器上处理了
In the MapReduce job we have three well-defined steps,
在 MapReduce 的任务里 我们有三个标准步骤
Map, shuffle, and reduce.
Map、shuffle 和 reduce
Let us assume that we stored our big log file on HDFS.
假设我们把数据存在HDFS 里
First, we need to break the data up into
首先我们要把数据分成
smaller chunks so commodity machines can handle the computational load.
一般商用电脑的计算能力可以处理的小块
Fortunately, HDFS we'll take care of this for us.
幸运的是 HDFS 会负责这部分内容
Let's call these chunks partitions.
我们把这些小块叫做分区
In the first step, each map processors partition from
在第一步里 每个 map处理器会在指定分区
disk transforms each record in that given partition,
对每个记录做转换
then rises modify records to an intermediate file.
把记录转换成中间文件
The transformation in this case consists of five steps,
这个转换过程在这个例子中包括 5 个步骤
we read each line of the log file,
先读取日志中的每一行数据
check if it's an event describing you use your listening to a song,
检查这个是否是描述你的用户听歌的数据的事件
then we check that the timestamp is in the correct range,
然后我们检查一下时间戳是否在正确的范围内
then extract the name of the song,
然后我们把歌名提取出来
and finally create a tuple with the name and the number one.
最后我们把歌名和数字 1 写成一个元组
At the end of the step,
最后
we will have multiple intermediate files
我们会有很多个中间文件
containing pairs of a song title and the number one.
里面是一堆由歌名和数字 1 组成的元组
These type of pairs show up a lot in big data and are called key-value pairs or tuples.
这类数据经常在大数据里出现 我们一般将其叫做键值对或元组
Even with four machines,
即使有四台机器
the data is so large.
数据量还是太大了
We will need many map processes one after another to Maestro all the records we have.
我们需要进行非常多的 map 处理才能把所有的记录转换完
Once all the map processes are complete,
一旦 map 的过程完毕了
the second step is the shuffle.
第二步就是 shuffle
All the records from these intermediate files are shuffled across the cluster,
所有的来自中间文件的记录会在集群中洗牌
so the pairs with the same song,
最终 相同歌名的键值对和
the key of the key value pair end up on the same machine.
拥有相同关键字的键值对会被存到同一台机器中
This way when the node aggregates the values for key,
这样 当这个节点对值按关键字进行汇总时
it can be sure that it has all the corresponding data for
就可以确保所有相同歌曲的键值对都在一台机器里了
a song and can compute the correct final result.
这样就可以计算正确的最终结果了
In the last, reduce step,
最后是 reduce 步骤
the values for a given key can be combined.
拥有相同关键字的键值对里的值会被放到一起
In this case, we just need to sum all the ones for a given key.
然后我们只要对每个关键字对应的1进行加总就行了
Finally the count results are written to the output files.
最后计数结果会被写到输出文件